# Bilegjargal Jargalsaikhan "Jargal"

Email: bjargal56@gmail.com Mobile: +1-641-451-3892

http://linkedin.com/in/bilegjargal-jargalsaikhan

#### SUMMARY

Highly impressed by Javascript technologies. Experienced in enterprise system development using ReactJS, NodeJS, and Agile/SCRUM software development lifecycle method. Have an understanding of functional and object-oriented programming. Get satisfied from problem-solving, supporting someone and learning. Willing to work with both front-end and back-end.

## **SKILLS**

- Frameworks: ReactJS, Angular, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Agile/SCRUM, Selenium, Jest
- Programming: Javascript(ES6), TypeScript, HTML, CSS, SASS, SQL, MongoDB
- Tools: Git, NPM, YARN, RESTful API, Ubuntu, Linux Mint

#### EXPERIENCE

**Career Note**: Completed on-campus studies and currently taking distance education courses to complete a Master's Degree in Computer Science(Available for full-time, W-2 employment)

## **DIGITALWORKS COMPANY**

Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia, Software Developer, Mar 2018 - Aug 2018

- Working on business tool for contract management as a full-stack software developer, using ReactJS Redux,NodeJS, ExpressJS, and MongoDB, contributing specific phases of software developement process, including sprint planning, development, unit testing, review meeting, and deployment.
- Created the feature that generates the contract payment schedule by weekly, monthly or custom time interval and creates an invoice automatically.
- Implemented the new function to add dynamic fields to the document. Resulting in the implementation time for new customer reduced by 30 percent.
- Implemented CI/CD(continuous integration/continuous delivery) to my team using cucumber.io-Gherkin syntax. As a result our production delivery became more reliable and bug free.

## **ITZONE COMPANY**

Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia, Software Developer, Sep 2015 - Mar 2018

- Contributed to ERP system development specially worked in the Supply Chain Management System and Customer Relationship Management System team. Used technologies are Javascript(ES6), C#, OracleSQL.
- Created a back-end logic to compute all types of transaction flows over the finance and inventory modules, Resulting improved business process of inventory and finance department workflow by 20 percent. And eradicates faulty transaction occurrence.
- In order to speed up the dynamic report load time, modified SQL queries. As a result dynamic report generating time fastened up to 8 times.
- Worked on client's site and solved many minor and major bugs and problems as a fast phased development. Awarded Customer happiness award in the first quarter of the year.

#### **EDUCATION**

• Maharishi University of Management Master of Science in Computer Science;

Fairfield, IOWA Aug. 2018 – In progress

• Mongolian University of Management Bachelor of Science in Computer Science; Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia Aug. 2012 – Jun. 2016